wintips.org 2019-10-08

# Privacy Policy - wintips.org - Windows Tips & How-tos

Last updated on July 5th, 2019

We're glad you chose to visit **www.wintips.org** site! We care about your privacy and the information you share with us and want you to understand how we are using and protecting the information we collect about you. **WinTips.ORG** is respectful of data privacy and adopts best practice in compliance with applicable privacy law and regulations, including the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR").

**WinTips.org** ("us", "we,") is committed to respecting the privacy rights of visitors and other users of www.wintips.org (the "Site").

This Policy is only applicable to this site ([www.wintips.org](http://www.wintips.org/)) and not to any other websites that you may be able to access from the Site, each of which may have data collection and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Policy.

This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by this Website ([www.wintips.org](http://www.wintips.org/)) and how it is used.

**BY ACCESSING, USING AND/OR DOWNLOADING THE SITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AND ALSO SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF OUR  [TERMS OF SERVICE](https://www.wintips.org/terms-of-service/). IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ALL OF THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT ACCESS, DOWNLOAD AND/OR USE THE SITE**. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy frequently, as it may change from time to time. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use the Site.

## PRIVACY POLICY SUMMARY

This is a summary of our privacy policy, to easy understand how we collect information from you, what information we collect and how we use and secure that information.

  * **How we collect or obtain information about you**

> 1\. When you provide it to us (e.g. by contacting us or when commenting to a post/article)  
>  2\. When visiting our website (e.g. from Usage Data, Logs and Cookies).

  * **What Information we collect**

> 1\. The name and your email address (only if you provide them to us).  
>  2\. Our website server records some basic information regarding user's visit sent by the web browser. No personal data is collected, the server only collects general information such as your IP address, information from cookies, information about your device type (e.g. computer or mobile), the browser you use, which pages you visited and when you visited them and your geographical location (based on your IP address).

  * **How we use your information**

> 1\. To reply to you when posting a comment or when contacting us using the [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/).  
>  2\. For administrative purposes only, like to improve this website, to analyze the use of our website and in connection with our legal rights and obligations.

  * **Share of information: NO  
**We do not disclose, sell or provide your personal data that you have submitted through comments or through our [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/), in any way to third parties.

  * **Disclosure of your information to third parties:**  
Only to the extent necessary to run our business, to our service providers and where required by law or to enforce our legal rights.

  * **How long we retain your information**  
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
  * **How we secure your information**  
This website takes all the appropriate security measures such as storing your information on secure servers, encrypting transfers of data to or from our servers using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. We recommend that you use anti-virus software, anti-malware, firewalls, and other precautions to protect yourself from security threats. If you become aware of any breach of Site security or this Privacy Policy, please notify us immediately.
  * **Use of cookies**  
This website use cookies to store information about visitors' preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.  
Promotions or advertisements displayed on our site may contain cookies. We do not have access to or control over information collected by outside advertisers on our site.
  * **Third Party Advertising**  
In this website we use third party advertisements in order to financially support the site. Some of these ads might make use of tools such as web beacons and cookies that could potentially also send these advertisers certain information like the web browser you are using to visit the site, whether you have flash installed on your system, your IP (internet protocol), or your ISP (Internet Service Provider). Personally identifiable information data, like name, address, email, phone number or similar are NOT included.

  * **Links to Third Party Websites**  
We have included links on this site for your use and reference. We are not responsible for the privacy policies on these websites. You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites might differ from our own.
  * **Transfers of your information outside the European Economic Area** : in certain circumstances we transfer your information outside of the European Economic Area, including to the United States of America. Where we do so, we will ensure appropriate safeguards are in place, including, for example, that the third parties we use who transfer your information outside the European Economic Area have self-certified themselves as compliant with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.
  * **Your rights in relation to your information**

> 1\. To get a copy of your stored personal data we hold about you.  
>  2\. To erase your personal data.

> Notice: This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## PRIVACY POLICY IN DETAILS.

##### What data we collect and how we collect them.

Among the types of Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: basic information (first name & email address), Usage Data, Logs & Cookies.

Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.

Complete details on each type of Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

##### Information we collect when you commenting to a post or when contacting us.

  * **Name & Email Address.  
**In operating the Site, we collect some basic information (name & email address) from you and only if you provide it to us, in a couple different situations.  
The first is if you should contact us via the "contact" page. In doing so, you will provide us with your name and email address.  
The second is if you leave a comment to a blog post during which you may be asked for a name and email address. You are not required to provide us with information via these two methods to use and enjoy the Site.

Personal Data are collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  *     * **Contact Form**
      * This Website contains information that enables a quick electronic contact with us, which also includes a general address of the so-called electronic mail (e-mail address).
      * If a data subject contacts the controller by e-mail or via a [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/), the personal data transmitted by the data subject are automatically stored. Such personal data transmitted on a voluntary basis by a data subject to the data controller are stored for the purpose of processing or contacting the data subject.
      * There is no transfer of this personal data to third parties.By filling in the [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/) with their Data, the User authorizes this Website to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form's header.
      * **Personal Data collected:** Email address and first name.

  *     * **Content commenting.**
      * Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Website.
      * Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments.
      * If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.
      * If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting service.
      * Comment system managed directly by this Website.
      * This Website has its own internal content comment system.
      * **P** **ersonal Data collected:** Email address & first name. ****

##### Information we collect when visiting our site.

  * **Usage Data.**
    * Our servers automatically recognize visitors' domain names and IP addresses (the number assigned to computers on the Internet). No personal information about you is revealed in this process. 
    * The Site may also gather anonymous "traffic data" that does not personally identify you, but that may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer.

  * **Log Files.**
    * Like many other Web sites, this Website makes use of log files.
    * The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information.
    * IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable

  * **Web Server.**
    * We use a third party server to host our website.
    * Our website server automatically logs the IP address you use to access our website as well as other information about your visit such as the pages accessed, information requested, the date and time of the request, the source of your access to our website (e.g. the website or URL (link) which referred you to our website), and your browser version and operating system.
    * Our third party hosting provider stores server logs to ensure network and IT security and so that the server and website remain uncompromised. This includes analyzing log files to help identify and prevent unauthorized access to our network, the distribution of malicious code, denial of services attacks and other cyber-attacks, by detecting unusual or suspicious activity.
    * Unless we are investigating suspicious or potential criminal activity, we do not make, nor do we allow our website server provider to make any attempt to identify you from the information collected via server logs.
    * **Our web server is located in:**  United States. We are hosted on a server provided by HawkHost inc. For information about HawkHost and how it collects and processes data, please visit its [Privacy Policy](https://www.hawkhost.com/Legal/privacy).
    * **Use of website server log information** for IT security purposes.
  * 

##### Other information we collect about you.

  * **Cookies.**
    * From time to time, we may use the standard "cookies" feature of major browser applications that allows us to store a small piece of data on your computer about your visit to our Site.
    * Cookies help us learn which areas of our Site are useful and which areas need improvement through programs including, but not limited to, Google Analytics.
    * We may also use cookies from third party social sites and programs including, but not limited to, Facebook, Google Plus and Twitter.
    * You can choose to disable cookies through your browser or independent programs available online. However, if you choose to disable this function, your experience at our Site may be diminished as some features may not work as they were intended.

**What are your choices regarding cookies.**

  * You may opt-out from Google's cookies using their [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated). You may also use the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) to opt-out of some third party cookies.
  * If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser. *

* Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly.

  *     * For the Chrome web browser, please visit this page from Google: <https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050>
    * For the Internet Explorer web browser, please visit this page from Microsoft: <http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835>
    * For the Firefox web browser, please visit this page from Mozilla: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored>
    * For the Safari web browser, please visit this page from Apple: [https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored)
    * For any other web browser, please visit your web browser's official web pages. **Where can you find more information about cookies.  
**You can learn more about cookies and the following third-party websites:

  *     * AllAboutCookies: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>
    * Network Advertising Initiative: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>

##### Information collected from Advertisers & third parties.

  * Our website employs the use the various third party services. Through the use of our website, these services may place anonymous cookies on the Visitor's browser and may send their own cookies to the Visitor's cookie file.
  * Some of these services include, but are not limited to: Google, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, StackPath, advertising agencies, analytics companies and service providers. These services may also collect and use anonymous identifiers such as IP Address, HTTP Referrer, Unique Device Identifier and other non-personally identifiable information and server logs.
  * **Type of Data collected:** Cookies & Usage Data.

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

##### **Advertising.**

We use third-party advertisements on this website such as Google AdSense to pay hosting server bills and to keep this website functional and running. These ad companies can use cookies or web beacons to collect some information about your visit to serve ads of interest to you.

You can manage, delete or turn them off any time using your web browser settings. You can also opt-out of the use of DART cookie by Google using this [link](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Website, possibly based on User interests. This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.

Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User's interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Website. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

  * **DoubleClick DART Cookie.**
    * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this Website.
    * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this Website and other sites on the Internet.
    * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>
    * You can use [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/) to manage the Google ads you see and opt out of Ads Personalization.

**D** **ata protection provisions about the application and use of Google AdSense**

On this website, the controller has integrated Google AdSense. Google AdSense is an online service which allows the placement of advertising on third-party sites. Google AdSense is based on an algorithm that selects advertisements displayed on third-party sites to match with the content of the respective third-party site. Google AdSense allows an interest-based targeting of the Internet user, which is implemented by means of generating individual user profiles.

The operating company of Google's AdSense component is Alphabet Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

The purpose of Google's AdSense component is the integration of advertisements on our website. Google AdSense places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Alphabet Inc. is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google AdSense component is integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google AdSense component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Alphabet Inc. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Alphabet Inc. gains knowledge of personal data, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Alphabet Inc., inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks and subsequently create commission settlements.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Alphabet Inc. from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. Additionally, cookies already in use by Alphabet Inc. may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

Furthermore, Google AdSense also uses so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic that is embedded in web pages to enable a log file recording and a log file analysis through which a statistical analysis may be performed. Based on the embedded tracking pixels, Alphabet Inc. is able to determine if and when a website was opened by a data subject, and which links were clicked on by the data subject. Tracking pixels serve, inter alia, to analyze the flow of visitors on a website.

Through Google AdSense, personal data and information—which also includes the IP address, and is necessary for the collection and accounting of the displayed advertisements—is transmitted to Alphabet Inc. in the United States of America. These personal data will be stored and processed in the United States of America. The Alphabet Inc. may disclose the collected personal data through this technical procedure to third parties.

Google AdSense is further explained under the following link <https://www.google.com/intl/en/adsense/start/>

  * **CJ Affiliate by Conversant**
    * CJ Affiliate by Conversant (formerly Commission Junction) is a affiliate marketing network, specializing in pay-for-performance programs that drive results for businesses around the world.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * For more details, please review their [Privacy Policy](https://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy). ****

##### **Analytics**

Like other websites, we also use Google Analytics service to understand the traffic coming towards our website and to make our website better. It helps us in understanding how visitors use our website so that we can improve their experience.Personal Data is collected using the following services:

  * **Google Analytics (Google Inc.)**
    * Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google").
    * Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.
    * Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

**Data protection provisions about the application and use of Google Analytics (with anonymization function).**

On this website, the controller has integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function).

Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.

The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.For the web analytics through Google Analytics the controller uses the application "_gat. _anonymizeIp". By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the data subject is abridged by Google and anonymized when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, inter alia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us.

Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlements.

The cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the data subject. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the data subject, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third parties.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

In addition, the data subject has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the data subject must download a browser add-on under the link https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the data subject is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the data subject must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the data subject or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/> and under <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link <https://www.google.com/analytics/>.

##### Interaction with external social networks and platforms.

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website.

The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User's privacy settings for each social network.

This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * **Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.)**
    * The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/).

**D** **ata protection provisions about the application and use of Google+**

On this website, the controller has integrated the Google+ button as a component. Google+ is a so-called social network. A social network is a social meeting place on the Internet, an online community, which usually allows users to communicate with each other and interact in a virtual space. A social network may serve as a platform for the exchange of opinions and experiences, or enable the Internet community to provide personal or business-related information. Google+ allows users of the social network to include the creation of private profiles, upload photos and network through friend requests.

The operating company of Google+ is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this website, which is operated by the controller and on which a Google+ button has been integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject automatically downloads a display of the corresponding Google+ button of Google through the respective Google+ button component. During the course of this technical procedure, Google is made aware of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. More detailed information about Google+ is available under <https://developers.google.com/+/>.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time to Google+, Google recognizes with each call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of his or her stay on our Internet site, which specific sub-pages of our Internet page were visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Google+ button and Google matches this with the respective Google+ account associated with the data subject.

If the data subject clicks on the Google+ button integrated on our website and thus gives a Google+ 1 recommendation, then Google assigns this information to the personal Google+ user account of the data subject and stores the personal data. Google stores the Google+ 1 recommendation of the data subject, making it publicly available in accordance with the terms and conditions accepted by the data subject in this regard. Subsequently, a Google+ 1 recommendation given by the data subject on this website together with other personal data, such as the Google+ account name used by the data subject and the stored photo, is stored and processed on other Google services, such as search-engine results of the Google search engine, the Google account of the data subject or in other places, e.g. on Internet pages, or in relation to advertisements.

Google is also able to link the visit to this website with other personal data stored on Google. Google further records this personal information with the purpose of improving or optimizing the various Google services.Through the Google+ button, Google receives information that the data subject visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call-up to our website is logged in to Google+. This occurs regardless of whether the data subject clicks or doesn't click on the Google+ button.

If the data subject does not wish to transmit personal data to Google, he or she may prevent such transmission by logging out of his Google+ account before calling up our website.

Further information and the data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. More references from Google about the Google+ 1 button may be obtained under [https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

  * **Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)**
    * The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

  * **LinkedIn –** **"Share on LinkedIn" Plugin button** **.**
    * The "Share on LinkedIn" Plugin button and social widgets are allowing interaction with the LinkedIn professional network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data. [Cookie Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy?src=li-other&veh=www.linkedin.com) – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=hb_ft_priv)

  * **Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)**
    * The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy).

**Data protection provisions about the application and use of Twitter  
**On this website, the controller has integrated components of Twitter.

Twitter is a multilingual, publicly-accessible micro blogging service on which users may publish and spread so-called 'tweets,' e.g. short messages, which are limited to 280 characters. These short messages are available for everyone, including those who are not logged on to Twitter. The tweets are also displayed to so-called followers of the respective user. Followers are other Twitter users who follow a user's tweets. Furthermore, Twitter allows you to address a wide audience via hashtags, links or retweets.

The operating company of Twitter is Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a Twitter component (Twitter button) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding Twitter component of Twitter. Further information about the Twitter buttons is available under <https://about.twitter.com/de/resources/buttons>. During the course of this technical procedure, Twitter gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

The purpose of the integration of the Twitter component is a retransmission of the contents of this website to allow our users to introduce this web page to the digital world and increase our visitor numbers. If the data subject is logged in at the same time on Twitter, Twitter detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Twitter component and associated with the respective Twitter account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Twitter buttons integrated on our website, then Twitter assigns this information to the personal Twitter user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Twitter receives information via the Twitter component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in on Twitter at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the Twitter component or not. If such a transmission of information to Twitter is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their Twitter account before a call-up to our website is made.

The applicable data protection provisions of Twitter may be accessed under <https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en>.

**Paypal.**  
In this website we have integrated the Paypal Donate button for donations from our users. We recommend that you read [Paypal's privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) prior to effecting any transactions with us.

##### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Website and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * **YouTube video widget (Google Inc.)**
    * YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

**Data protection provisions about the application and use of YouTube.  
**On this website, the controller has integrated components of YouTube. YouTube is an Internet video portal that enables video publishers to set video clips and other users free of charge, which also provides free viewing, review and commenting on them. YouTube allows you to publish all kinds of videos, so you can access both full movies and TV broadcasts, as well as music videos, trailers, and videos made by users via the Internet portal.The operating company of YouTube is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, UNITED STATES. The YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding YouTube component.Further information about YouTube may be obtained under <https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/>. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the data subject.

YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject has visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call to our website is logged in on YouTube; this occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on a YouTube video or not. If such a transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a call-up to our website is made.YouTube's data protection provisions, available at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>, provide information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.

  * **Google Fonts (Google Inc.)**
    * Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/policies/privacy/) _._
    * **Place of processing:** United States.

##### SPAM protection

This type of services analyzes the traffic of this Website, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

Personal Data is collected using the following services:

  * **Akismet (Automattic Inc.)**
    * Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by [Automattic Inc](https://automattic.com/).
    * **Personal Data collected:** various types of Data as specified in the [privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) of the service.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

  * **Google reCAPTCHA (Google Inc.)**
    * Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google Inc.
    * The use of reCAPTCHA is subject to the Google [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and [terms of use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and Usage Data.
    * **Place of processing:** United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. ****

**Gravatar  
**We use the Gravatar service provided by Automattic inc. When visitors leave comments on the site an anonymized string created from their email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service. After approval of the comment, the profile picture which is provided by Gravatar will be publicly visible in the context of the comment. For information about Gravatar and how it collects and processes data, please visit its privacy policy: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

**Jetpack  
**We use Jetpack, a tool for statistical evaluation of accesses by visitors that is operated by Automattic, Inc., using a tracking technology by Quantcast Inc. You can opt-out to the collection and use of the data by Quantcast at <https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out/>. You can find out more about how Jetpack and Quantacast collect and process data by visiting their respective privacy policy pages at <https://jetpack.com/support/privacy/> and <https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/>

##### Traffic optimization and distribution.

This type of service allows this Website to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Website and the User's browser.

Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

Personal Data is collected using the following services:

  * **StackPath**
    * StackPath is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by [StackPath, LLC](https://www.stackpath.com/).
    * The way StackPath is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Website, i.e., communication between this Website and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Website to be collected.
    * **Personal Data collected:** Cookies and various types of Data as specified in their [privacy policy](https://www.stackpath.com/privacy-statement/) of the service. ** **

##### Who we share your data with.

We do not share personal information with third-parties nor do we store information we collect about your visit to this blog for use other than to analyze content performance through the use of cookies, which you can turn off at any time by modifying your Internet browser's settings. We are not responsible for the republishing of the content found on this website on other Web sites or media without our permission.

  * **Personal Information  
**When you provide your email address while posting a comment or while contacting us using the contact page, _we never share it with anyone_. Your email address will only be used for responding to your email or comment and will never be shared or made publicly available. Additionally, these data will never be used by www.wintips.org or by a third party for sending news about our service or for sending promotional material. __

  * **Usage Data**.  
We use anonymous information to analyze our Site traffic and content performance through the use of cookies, which you can turn off at any time by modifying your Internet browser's settings.  
In addition, we may use anonymous IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, or to display the content according to your preferences.  
Traffic and transaction information may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate and anonymous basis.

##### Disclosure of Personal Information.

We may disclose any information we have for you if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on us, (2) protect and defend our rights or property or the users of the Site, or (3) act under exigent circumstances to protect the safety of the public or users of the Site.

##### Retention time.

If you leave a comment, your email address, your name, your comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

##### How we protect your Data.

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), the industry standard, for encrypting all personal information, including first name and email address.

BUT, keep in mind that, _no data transmission over the Internet is entirely secure_ and _no system of physical or electronic security is impenetrable_. We cannot guarantee the security of the information you send or the security of our servers and databases. By using our Services you agree to assume all risk in connection with the information sent to us or collected by us when you use our Services. In the unlikely event that we believe the security of your information may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you.

##### What rights you have over your data.

You can request from us, using the [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/), to receive an exported file of the personal data that we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

You can request from us, using the [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/) to erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

Additionally, if you want to delete a comment made by you on an article page of this website due to privacy reasons, you can request us using the [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/) and we'll remove your comment within 24 hours.

##### Data transfer outside the EU.

The Owner is allowed to transfer Personal Data collected within the EU to third countries (i.e. any country not part of the EU) only pursuant to a specific legal basis. Any such Data transfer is based on one of the legal bases described below.

Information you submit to us by email or by using the contact form, is transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA) and stored on our web server.

**Country of storage:** United States of America

##### Data transfer from the EU and/or Switzerland to the U.S based on Privacy Shield (this Website)

If this is the legal basis, the transfer of Personal Data from the EU or Switzerland to the US is carried out according to the EU – U.S. and Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield.

In particular, Personal Data is transferred to services that self-certify under the Privacy Shield framework and therefore guarantee an adequate level of protection of such transferred Data. All services are listed within the relevant section of this document and those that adhere to Privacy Shield can be singled out by checking their privacy policy and possibly also by specifically checking for Privacy Shield adherence in the official Privacy Shield List. Privacy Shield also specifically guarantees rights to Users which can be found in its most current form on the website run by the US Department of Commerce.

Personal Data may be transferred from within the EU or Switzerland to the U.S. to services that are not, or not anymore, part of Privacy Shield, only based on other valid legal grounds. Users can ask the Owner to learn about such legal grounds.

**Personal Data collected:** various types of Data.

##### Legal Information.

  * **Legal action  
**The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.
  * **Legal Reference  
**This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).  
This privacy policy relates solely to this Website, if not stated otherwise within this document.

##### Online Privacy Policy Only.

This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website and regarding information shared and/or collected there. This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

##### Changes to this privacy policy.

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within this Website and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Website and can request that the Owner remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Owner has about Users.

##### Notice concerning children.

We encourage parents and guardians to spend time discussing with minors their online activity, so as to be fully familiar with the websites they visit and the apps they use. Our Site is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Site. If you are under 13, do not use this Site, register an Account, or provide any information about yourself to us.

Our Services is not intended for use by children, especially those under the age 13. No one under 13 years of age is allowed to provide any persona information or use our public forums, chats, etc. Minors between 13 – 17 years of age must get permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before using our Services. If we discover that we have received any personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information as quickly as possible. ****

##### Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to its privacy policy and agree to its [terms of service](https://www.wintips.org/terms-of-service/). If you do not agree, you must immediately stop using our website.

##### Contact.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, or would like to make any requests in relation to your Personal Information, please feel free to contact us by sending us an email at: info (@) wintips.org or by using this [contact form](https://www.wintips.org/contact/).

**Last update:** May 23, 2018
